******g is not technically yogurt,
知道了吧 你吃的这个 不算是真的酸奶酪
because it doesn't have enough live acidophilus cultures.
因为里面没有足够的 活的嗜酸培养菌
It's really just ice milk with carrageenan added for thickness.
只不过是冰牛奶里加了点 角叉胶 增加粘稠度
Oh,that's very interesting.
喔 真有意思哈
It's also not pink and has no berries.
它也不真是粉红色 也没有天然浆果粒
Yeah,but it doesn't really answer my question.
嗯 可这也没有回答我的问题呐
What was your question again?
你问的啥问题?
Do you want some?
你要来点儿不?
Right. No.
对对 不用了
- I'm lactose intolerant. - Right.
- 我受不了乳糖的 - 对哦
- So,gas. - Yeah,got it.
- 吃了会放屁的 - 好吧 明白了
Well... good night.
那么... 晚安了
What are you doing?
你这是做什么呢?
Oh,there's a draft.
哦 那边有阵风
I didn't feel a draft.
我没觉得有风啊
Why don't we just go into,uh,your...
那我们还是去... 你的...
Yeah,you know what,maybe we should slow things down a little.
我说 也许我们不该那么着急
No,no,I didn't mean to go into your apartment to go fast.
不 我不是说要去你公寓 去急着干嘛干嘛
No,I know.
当然了 我知道
I know what you meant,it's just... this is only our first date.
我知道你不是那意思 只是... 这才是咱俩第一次约会
Yeah,okay,sure,no problem.
嗯 好啊 没问题
Why don't we just figure out where we're going and when we want to get there,
那我们就先想想 下次要去哪儿 准备啥时候到那儿
and then rate of speed equals distance over time.
这样距离除以时间 就知道速度了呗
Solve for R.
问题解决
Or we could just wing it.
我们也可以到时候再想嘛
That might work,too.
那没准也行
- Good night,Leonard. - Good night.
- 晚安 Leonard - 晚安
He's coming-- screensaver!
他来了 快上屏保!
Oh,hey,Leonard. How was your date?
嘿 Leonard 约会怎么样哇?
Bite me.
要你管
Sheldon,how could you just sit there and let them spy on me?
Sheldon 你怎么能傻坐着 眼睁睁看他们监视我呢?
They were clever,Leonard.
他们油菜啊 Leonard
They exploited my complete lack of interest in what you were doing.
他们完全明白 我对你那些破事儿 一点兴趣没有
You should thank us.
你还该谢谢我们呢
When future generations try to determine why your relationship with Penny crashed and burned,
要是后来人想弄明白 你和Penny的恋情为啥会土崩瓦解
this right here is the black box.
这玩意儿就是黑匣子呐!
What are you talking about? The date went fine.
你胡说什么 约会挺好的
Dude,she said she wants to slow things down.
拜托 她都说了 想要慢慢来
Okay,so she said she wants to slow things down.
好吧 她是说了 想要慢慢来
It's like saying,"I'm really enjoying this meal.
意思差不多就是 "今天的晚餐我非常喜欢
I'm going to slow down and savor it."
我得慢慢来 好好回味一下"
No,it's like,"This fish tastes bad,
才怪 她的意思是 "这鱼真难吃死了
so I'm gonna slow down and spit it out."
我得慢慢来 吐光了它"
- You being the fish. - I'm not the fish.
- 这臭鱼说的就是你! - 我才不是这臭鱼呢
Oh,really? Did you make a second date?
真的? 你俩定了下一次约会吗?
Well,no,we sort of decided to wing it.
这倒没有... 我们说好了 到时候再想
Oh,even I know that's lame.
得了吧 连我都觉得这太逊了
Okay,all right,let's assume your hypothesis.
行啊 咱就说说你的假设
We went to dinner,we talked,we laughed,we kissed.
我们一起去吃饭 有说有笑 有吻有抱
Where could I have possibly gone wrong?
这还能错到哪儿去啊?
Think back,Leonard.
你好好想想 Leonard
The littlest things can set women off.
再小的事情都能让女人爆发
Like,"Hey,the waitress is hot,I bet we could get her to come home with us."
比方说 "嘿 这服务生真辣 我打赌 肯定能让她跟咱回家"
Or,"How much does your mom weigh?
或者 "你妈妈有多重呐?
I want to know what I'm getting into."
我想知道我搭上的是啥样的妞儿"
I didn't say anything like that.
这种话我才不会说
Good,'cause they don't work.
很好 因为这么说不管用
They also don't care for it if you stare at them and hyperventilate.
她们也不关心 你是不是盯着她们 呼吸加速
Sadly,that's my home run swing.
挺惨的 在我们家 这就像是家族传统
Look,everything went fine.
我说 一切都挺好的
I didn't even have to refer to my impromptu conversation starters.
连事先准备的一些开场白都没用到呢
That woman across the hall is into me.
走廊对面那个女孩 就是喜欢我嘛
Let's go to the tape.
咱还是看带子吧
Look at her reaction to the good night kiss.
你瞧她临别一吻的时候 那反应
No change in respiration,pupils un-dilated,no flushing of the chest.
呼吸平稳 瞳孔没有放大 胸口也没啥起伏
Nice close-up,by the way.
这特写镜头拍的真赞
Interesting. Her jaws are clenched: no tongue access.
有意思嘿 她的下巴很紧 也没有用舌头
Clearly a bad sign amongst mating humans.
对于寻偶期的人类来说 这可不是啥好消息
That's not a bad sign.
这怎么就不是好消息了
Please,you might as well have been two iguana with no dewlap enlargement.
得了吧 还不如说你们是两只鬣蜥 只是喉部没有垂肉罢了
And the worst sign of all is you're here and not there.
最糟的就是 这会儿你不在她家 而在这里!
I'm not there because I'm taking things slow,which,
我不在她家 因为我也决定慢慢来 这个...
by the way,compared to you guys,approaches warp speed.
跟你们比起来 都快接近星际速度了
And take down that camera.
快把摄像头给我撤了
He was a lot more fun when he had no hope.
他心里没牵没挂的时候 真有意思多了
Give him time.
给他点时间吧
Oh,hi,Penny.
你好啊 Penny
FYI,the hot water is inadequate on machine two,so colors only,
顺便说句 2号机器的热水不足 别深色浅色混着洗
and four is still releasing the fabric softener too early in the cycle,
4号机器呢 洗衣程序中 还是会提前放出织物柔顺剂
so I'd avoid using that for your delicates.
所以你那些精致的衣服 还是别用那台了
Thanks.
谢了
Oh,good Lord...
老天爷啊...
why don't you just take your clothes down to the river and beat them with a rock?
你还不如把衣服拿到河边 搁在石头上猛捶一阵
Sheldon,can I ask you a question?
Sheldon 我问你个问题行不?
I would prefer that you not,but I won't go so far as to forbid it.
我当然最好你别问 不过也不会阻止你
All right,I heard yes,so...
那... 我就当你同意了...
Okay,here's my question.
我想问问你
Has Leonard ever dated, you know,a regular girl?
Leonard以前有没有 跟正常的女孩子约会过?
Well,I assume you're not referring to digestive regularity.
我想你指的 应该不是消化功能正常吧
Because I've come to learn that such inquiries are inappropriate.
要是那样的话 我想这问题问的不合适
No,I meant,has he ever been involved with someone who wasn't a brainiac?
我是说 他有没有跟 没那么大学问的女孩子谈过?
Well,a few years ago,he did go out with a woman who had a PhD in French literature.
话说几年前 他确实跟一个 学法国文学的女博士有过一段儿
How is that not a brainiac?
这还不算有大学问?
Well,for one thing,she was French.
理由一 她是法国人
For another,it was literature.
理由二 她读的是文学
So...
那你觉得...
do you think that if Leonard and I keep dating,he'll eventually get bored with me?
如果我和Leonard继续好下去 他会不会有一天觉得我很没劲啊?
- That depends. - On what?
- 那得看情况 - 什么情况?
- Do you have a working knowledge of quantum physics? - No.
- 你懂量子物理吗? - 不懂
- Do you speak Klingon? - No.
- 你会说克林贡语吗?(星际迷航) - 不会
- You know any card tricks? - Okay,you know what...
- 你会耍牌吗? - 行了 我说...
I get it.
我明白了
Leonard has no business being involved with a waitress-slash-actress
Leonard和一个服务员兼二流演员 没有共同语言
who felt so insecure that she lied to him about finishing community college.
而且她还骗他说 上完了社区大学 心里正发慌呢
Why would you lie about that?
你为什么撒谎?
Well,he was going on and on about this college and that grad school,and I...
他总是在说这大学怎样 那个研究生院怎么样 我就...
I didn't want him to think I was some kind of stupid loser.
我不想让他觉得我很傻很衰嘛
You thought the opposite of "stupid loser" was "community college graduate"?
你觉得"很傻很衰"的反义词 是"社区大学毕业生"?
You know,there are a lot of successful people in this country who are community college graduates.
很多成功人士 都是从社区大学毕业的
Yeah,but you are neither.
没错 可你哪个都挨不上边
Right. Okay,look,this is between you and me.
对 好吧 你得替我保密
You cannot tell Leonard any of this.
啥也不要告诉Leonard
- You're asking me to keep a secret? - Yeah.
- 你要我保守秘密? - 是的
Well,I'm sorry,but you would have had to express that desire before revealing the secret,
那真对不起了 你应该在说出秘密前 表达出要我保密的意思
so that I could choose whether or not I wanted to accept the covenant of secret keeping.
我好选择 到底要不要替你保密
You can't impose a secret on an ex post facto basis.
你事后再说 这怎么行呢
What?
什么?
Secret keeping is a complicated endeavor.
保守秘密是一项艰巨复杂的任务
One has to be concerned not only about what one says,
不但要注意说的话
but about facial expressions, autonomic reflexes.
还得注意面部表情 习惯性反应
When I try to deceive,I myself have more nervous tics than a Lyme disease research facility.
我说谎的时候 因为紧张产生的扁虱(tick) 比莱姆关节炎研究设备产生的还多
It's a joke.
这是笑话啊
It relies on the homonymic relationship between "tick,"
同音词嘛 "tick"是指
the bloodsucking arachnid,and "tic," the involuntary muscular contraction.
吸血蜘蛛 而"tic"是无意识的肌肉痉挛
I made it up myself.
我自己编的
Okay,look,if Leonard finds out that I lied,I will absolutely die of embarrassment.
听着 如果Leonard发现我说谎 我一定羞愧自尽了
Physiologically impossible.
生理学上讲是不可能的
Oh,Sheldon,please.
哦 Sheldon 拜托
Look,I am asking you as a friend.
我是以朋友的名义请求你
So you're saying that friendship contains within it an inherent obligation to maintain confidences?
照你这么说 朋友就要无条件的保守秘密?
Well,yeah.
是啊
Interesting.
有意思
One more question,and perhaps I should have led with this.
再一个问题 或许应该这样问
When did we become friends?
我们什么时候成朋友了?
i.e.,I couldn't become Green Lantern unless I was chosen by the Guardians of Oa,
也就是说 要不被总部守护先知选中 我就成不了绿灯侠 (漫画形象)
but given enough start-up capital and an adequate research facility,I could be Batman.
但如果给我足够的启动资金和 足够的科研设备 我就能成为蝙蝠侠
- You could be Batman? - Sure. I'm Batman. See?
- 你能成为蝙蝠侠? - 当然 我就是蝙蝠侠 看见没?
- Hi,guys. - Hi,Penny.
- 嗨 伙计们 - 嗨 Penny
Penny,if you're not doing anything Friday night,I thought maybe we could go see a movie.
Penny 你周五晚上有空的话 我们去看电影吧
Oh,um,you know,I think I have the dinner shift on Friday.
呃 我周五晚上要轮班
Okay,what about Saturday?
好吧 周六呢?
You know,I'm not sure; the manager hasn't posted the schedule yet.
说不准 经理还没公布排班表呢
- How about I let you know? - Great.
- 出来了 我再告诉你? - 很好
So you just let me know when you know. Okay,so...
那你知道了就告诉我 好的 那...
Oh,God,I am the bad fish.
天呐 我就是那条臭鱼
What did I do wrong?
我哪做错了?
Why are you asking me?
你为什么问我?
I have no information about your interactions with Penny other than what you have provided me,
你和Penny的事儿 除了你已经告诉我的 我啥也不知道
nor do I have any method of learning such things.
我也没有本事学到
- What does that mean? - Nothing.
- 这话什么意思? - 没什么
You seem to be implying an informational back-channel
你说的倒像是 我和Penny背地里通了气
between me and Penny where obviously none exists.
很明显 这是没有的事
No,I didn't.
没 我没觉得
I just think you need to be careful how you phrase things,sir.
我想你要注意你的表达了 先生
What's going on with you?
你怎么回事?
I might ask you the same question.
这问题我也得问问你吧
Why do you insist on attempting to drag me into matters which have nothing to do with me,
那些跟我无关的事儿 你何必非要把我扯进去?
but exist between you and Penny, a person to whom I barely speak?
都是你和Penny之间的事 我跟她连话都不怎么说的
What's wrong with your face?
你脸怎么了?
There's no reason to bring my looks into this.
我脸这样 没啥原因
- Good day,Leonard. - What
- 祝你今天过的愉快 Leonard - 什么?
I said,"Good day."
我说 "祝你今天过的愉快"
Good day?
过的愉快?
Also today,we have a fresh-caught Alaska salmon,
今天还为您供应 新鲜的阿拉斯加大马哈鱼
and that's served with a teriyaki glaze and sticky rice.
配上烧汁和糯米饭
Our soup of the day is...
今天的汤是...
You must release me from my oath.
你必须将我从我的誓言中解放出来
Sheldon,I'm working.
Sheldon 我在工作
Why don't you take a minute to decide?
你们花几分钟决定一下吧
I can't keep your secret,Penny.
我不能保守你的秘密了 Penny
I'm going to fold like an energy-based de novo protein in conformational space.
我就像构象空间里 基于能量的内源蛋白 要折叠起来了 (fold 也有失败的意思)
Like a Renaissance tryptich.
就像是文艺复兴时期的三联画 (教堂祭坛上的饰物 两翼可向内折叠)
Like a cheap suit.
还有廉价的西装
Look,why is it so hard for you to keep one little secret?
你保守个小秘密 咋就这么难呢?
I'm constitutionally incapable.
我天生就保守不住!
That's why I was refused clearance for a very prestigious government research fellowship
所以我上次申请那项高端政府研究奖学金 证明开不出来
at a secret military supercollider located beneath a fake agricultural station
项目里的超级对撞机 位于密歇根州 Traverse城东南12.5英里的
12.5 miles southeast of Traverse City,Michigan.
一个空设的农学院地下
Which you did not hear about from me.
我没告诉过你啊
Look,just forget I told you about me...
你就别老记着我说过...
not graduating from community college,okay?
社区大学没毕业 好吗?
Forget? You want me to forget?
别老记着? 这能忘得掉吗?
This mind does not forget.
我这脑子 啥东西忘得掉啊!
I haven't forgotten a single thing since the day my mother stopped breastfeeding me.
从我妈给我断奶后 我就没忘掉过一件事
- It was a drizzly Tuesday. - Okay...
- 那天是周二 下着毛毛雨 - 好了...
Look,you promised me you would keep my secret,
你答应过我要保守秘密
so you're just gonna have to figure out a way to do it.
那你就想个办法别漏嘴
Leonard,I'm moving out.
Leonard 我要搬出去
What do you mean you're moving out? Why?
什么叫"要搬出去"? 为什么?
There doesn't have to be a reason.
不一定非要有理由嘛
Yeah,there kinda does.
是啊 总该有吧
Not necessarily.
不一定非得有
This is a classic example of Munchausen's Trilemma.
这是Munchausen三难推理的典型例子
Either the reason is predicated on a series of sub-reasons leading to an infinite regression,
要么就是 这个前提通过一系列 不断弱化的次前提 已经得到阐述
or it tracks back to arbitrary axiomatic statements,
要么就是 能从所谓偶然的公理陈述中 找到答案
or it's ultimately circular,
也有可能是终极循环
i.e.I'm moving out because I'm moving out.
也就是说 因为我要搬出去 所以我要搬出去
I'm still confused.
我还是不懂
Leonard,I don't see how I could have made it any simpler.
Leonard 我已经说得够明白的了
Hey,qu'est que s'up?
嘿 伙计们 还好吗? (蹩脚法语)
We just got back from that exhibit of those plasticized human cadavers.
我们刚去看了塑化人体标本展
And some of those skinless chicks were Hot!
那些个没皮的小妞儿 真是辣哟!
If you'll excuse me,I'm going to pack.
抱歉 我得去收拾了
That's kind of an overreaction to a little harmless necrophilia.
他对我单纯的恋尸癖 反应还真大
It's not you,Howard. He says he's moving out.
Howard 不关你事 他说他要搬出去
What did you do?
你对他干了啥?
Did you change the contrast or brightness settings on the television?
你改了电视机的对比度和亮度?
No.
没啊
Did you take a Band-Aid off in front of him?
你在他面前扒了创可贴?
No.
没
Did you buy generic ketchup, forget to rinse the sink,
你买了三无番茄酱? 忘了洗水池?
talk to him through the bathroom door?
还是隔着厕所门同他讲话?
Adjust the thermostat,cook with cilantro,pronounce the "t" in often?
调了恒温器? 煮菜放了芫荽叶? "t"那音总是忘了发?
No.
没有
Did you make fun of trains?
你是不是拿火车开玩笑了?
No,I didn't do anything. He's just gone insane.
没有 我啥都没干 他疯了
Well,we all knew this day was coming.
也是 这天迟早会来的
Well,that was fast.
你动作还真快
It's my pre-packed disaster evacuation bag.
这是我早准备好的避难行囊
It's recommended by the Department of Homeland Security.
国土安全部推荐的
And Sarah Connor.
还有Sarah Connor ("终结者"女主人公)
Where are you going to live?
你打算住哪儿?
Until I find a permanent place,I will stay with friends.
在我找到寓所之前 我先在朋友家挤挤
Bye.
回见
Well... you can't stay with me.
呃... 你不能住我那儿
I have a teeny-tiny apartment.
我的公寓小得可怜
Excuse me,but isn't hosting guests an aspect of "manushya yajna,"
广纳宾客不正是"向人致敬"的一部分吗?
one of the five central religious duties or sacrifices of the Hindu householder?
"向人致敬"不是印度五大宗教戒规之一吗?
I hate trains.
我讨厌火车
Don't be ridiculous,you love trains.
别开玩笑了 你可喜欢火车了
Yes,I do. Come on.
啊 没错 来吧
See you later,Leonard.
回见 Leonard
This could work.
还真管用
This is a very old building.
这栋楼有年头了
60 years. It used to be a watch factory.
造了六十年了 以前是手表厂
What?
怎么了?
Don't you worry about the residual radium from the luminous dials?
你不担心残留在发光表盘里的镭吗?
Not until now!
你干嘛要提!
I can't believe I didn't bring my Geiger counter.
我竟然没带盖格计数器 (用于测量放射性物质)
I had it on my bed and I didn't pack it.
就在床头 我居然没拿
Well,if you're not comfortable staying here,Sheldon...
那么... Sheldon 要是你觉得住着不舒服
I'm kidding,I packed it.
我开玩笑的 我带来了
It was a joke.
是个笑话
I was subverting the conversational expectations.
我就是要破坏你的语境期待
I believe they call that the,uh,ol' switcharoo.
那叫啥来着 "出其不意"
(语言的突然变化 以求意想不到的效果)
Terrific.
好极了
Is that woman Aishwarya Rai?
那女的是Aishwarya Rai吗? (印度当红影星)
Yes,isn't she an amazing actress?
是的 她是个很棒的演员吧
Actually,I'd say she's a poor man's Madhuri Dixit.
我倒觉得她是可怜虫心中的Madhuri Dixit (印度90年代知名影星 后结婚生子)
How dare you!
你敢再说一遍!
Aishwarya Rai is a goddess.
Aishwarya Rai是我的女神
By comparison,Madhuri Dixit is a leprous prostitute.
相比之下 Madhuri Dixit 就是得麻风病的妓女
Sorry,I didn't mean to offend you.
对不起 我没想到会冒犯你
Obviously,you're not that familiar with Indian cinema.
显然你不了解印度电影
Who is it?
谁啊?
Stripper-Gram!
脱衣舞娘来喽!
Tag,you're It.
交给你了
Shouldn't you put him in a brown paper bag and set him on fire?
你就不能把他塞进牛皮纸袋里 烧了算了?
I've never slept on an air mattress before.
我从来没睡过气垫床
No lumbar support whatsoever.
腰部都没东西撑着
Maybe you'd be happier on a park bench.
你大概是想睡公园的长椅上是吧
I don't see any way to get a park bench in here.
我认为 你没有办法把长椅弄到这儿来
Do you want to switch?
要换一下吗?
No,that's fine.
不用了 这样挺好
I'm perfectly comfortable sleeping on a bouncy castle.
睡在充气城堡上可舒服呢
Get out of bed. We're switching.
下床来 我和你换
- Now,only if you want to. - Just get in the bed!
- 我没逼着你换 - 快下床!
What's going on?
这是怎么了?
Are you boys roughhousing?
你们两个臭小子 闹什么闹?
We're just talking,Ma!
老妈 我们只是在聊天!
If you don't settle down right now,
要是你们再不给我安生点
I'm not going to let you have any more sleepovers!
看我以后还让不让你去朋友家过夜!
For God's sake,Ma,I'm 27 years old!
老天啊 老妈 我都27了!
And it's not even a school night!
明天又不上学!
Comfy now?
舒服了吧?
That poster of Halle Berry is a little unnerving.
那张Halle Barry的海报让我有点紧张 (好莱坞女星 曾出演猫女)
So don't look at it.
别看就是了
She's like my fourth favorite Catwoman.
她是我第四爱的猫女郎
No kidding.
不是吧
Yeah,Julie Newmar,Michelle Pfieffer,Eartha Kitt,and then her.
对 前三个是Julie Newmar Michelle Pfieffer 和Eartha Kitt
What about Lee Merriweather?
Lee Merriweather呢?
Oh,I forgot about Lee Merriweather.
噢 我把她忘了
Well,I'm glad that's settled.
好吧 终于搞定了
That makes Halle Berry my fifth favorite Catwoman.
那Halle Barry只能排第五了
It's Julie Newmar,Michelle Pfieffer, Eartha Kitt,Lee Merriweather--
Julie Newmar  Michelle Pfieffer Eartha Kitt  Lee Merriweather...
Please,I'm begging you. Go to sleep.
求求你了 睡觉吧
I'm trying. I'm counting Catwomen.
我在努力嘛 都在数猫女郎了
She did make a fine mutant in the X-Men movies,though.
她在X战警里演的变种人倒是不赖
Oh,for God's sake.
噢 我求求你了
She's not my favorite of the X-Men.
X战警里我最喜欢的不是她
In order that would be: Wolverine,Cyclops--
要排序的话应该是:金钢狼 雷射眼
Oh,wait,I forgot Professor X.
噢 等等 我忘了X教授
Professor X,Wolverine,Cyclops, Iceman,then Storm,Angel,the Beast--
X教授 金钢狼 雷射眼 冰人 然后是暴风女 天使 还有野兽
No,wait,Nightcrawler.
不对 等等 还有蓝魔人
Professor X,Nightcrawler,Wolverine, Cyclops,Iceman,then Storm,Angel...
X教授 蓝魔人 金钢狼 雷射眼 冰人 暴风女 天使...
I'm coming!
来了!
There he is. There my old buddy bud bud.
是他 我的老-伙-计
What's with him?
他是怎么了?
Koothrappali dumped him on me, and he couldn't get to sleep,
Koothrappali把他扔给了我 他睡不着觉
so I gave him a glass of warm milk with a handful of my mom's Valium in it...
所以我给他倒了杯温牛奶 里面放了一把我妈的安眠药
but he still wouldn't shut up,so tag,you're It.
可他还是不肯住嘴 得了 还给你吧
I'm ba-a-a-ack.
我回...来了
I still don't know why you left.
我还是不知道你为啥要走
I can't tell you.
不能告诉你
Why not?
为什么?
I promised Penny.
我答应过Penny
You promised Penny what?
你答应她什么了?
I wouldn't tell you the secret.
我答应她保密啊
What secret? Tell me the secret.
什么秘密? 快告诉我
Mom smokes in the car.
老妈在车里抽烟
Jesus is okay with it but we can't tell Dad.
耶稣觉得没问题 不过不能告诉老爸
Not that secret. The other secret.
不是这个 另一个秘密
- I'm Batman-- Shh! - Damn it! Sheldon!
- 我是蝙蝠侠 嘘! - 我靠! Sheldon!
You said Penny told you a secret. What's the secret?
你说 Penny跟你说了个秘密 什么秘密?
Okay,I'll tell you,but you can't tell Leonard.
好吧 我告诉你 不过你不能告诉Leonard
I promise.
我保证
Penny lied about graduating from community college
Penny说她是社区大学毕业 其实没这回事
'cause she's afraid she's not smart enough for Leonard.
因为她怕自己不够聪明 配不上Leonard
So it's nothing I did? It's her problem?
不是我做错什么了? 是她的问题?
I drank milk that tasted funny.
我喝了杯牛奶 味道真好玩儿
Penny thinks I'm too smart for her. That's ridiculous.
Penny觉得我太聪明 这也太搞笑了
I know.
我明白
Most of your work is extremely derivative.
你的大部分工作 都不是原创的
And don't worry,that's not a secret.
别担心 这就不是秘密了
Everybody knows.
谁都知道
Listen,I know what's been bothering you about us,and I have the answer.
听着 我已经知道我们之间的问题了 我也有了解决方案
What are you talking about?
你在说什么?
Okay,first,I want to say that it's not Sheldon's fault.
好的 首先 这不是Sheldon的错
He tried very hard to keep your secret.
他已经很努力地替你保密了
If Howard hadn't drugged him,he would've taken it to his grave.
要不是Howard给他灌了安眠药 他是不会自掘坟墓的
He told you?
他告诉你了?
Yes,but it's okay.
是的 不过这没关系
Now that we know what the problem is there's a simple solution.
既然我们都知道问题何在 要解决岂不是很容易
Pasadena City College?
帕萨迪纳城市学院? (托福分数线最低的学校之一)
A place for fun,a place for knowledge.
"给你知识 给你乐趣"
See,this man here is playing hackey-sack, and this girl's gonna be a paralegal.
看见没? 这男的在玩沙包球 那女的会成为律师助手
Oh,I get it.
噢 我明白了
Because Dr. Leonard Hofstadter can't date a girl without a fancy college degree.
Leonard Hofstadter博士没法和一个 没有名牌大学文凭的女孩子谈恋爱
Well,it's really not that fancy.
嗯... 其实这也不是个名校
It's just a city college.
只是城市学院而已
Right,but I have to have some sort of degree to date you?
没错 不过要和你约会 总得有个学位什么的是吧?
That doesn't matter to me at all.
这对我而言一点都不重要
So it's fine with you if I'm not smart.
所以如果我不聪明也没关系
Absolutely.
绝对没关系
Okay,this time,I know where I went wrong.
好吧 这次我知道我错在哪儿了
Bite me!
你能拿我怎么样啊?!